<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Announcement | Phx Tag Soup]]></title>
  <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/categories/announcement/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-08T10:12:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Phx Tag Soup]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meteor.js Meeting Details]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/11/08/meteor-dot-js-meeting-details/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-08T09:51:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/11/08/meteor-dot-js-meeting-details</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Meteor JS Team Member Avital Oliver!</h3>

<h4>Meeting time and date: 7pm (Arizona Time), Nov 15th, 2012</h4>

<p>We're really excited about this one. I remember when I first saw Meteor.js. I think @0lu, @rxgx or @phil_renaud sent it to me. It was probably the day it launched. Srsly amazeballs. The only thing that kept me from really falling in love with it was the lack of security. That's all changed now...</p>

<p>Fast forward to Oct 17th (or maybe at this point I should say rewind). This <a href="http://meteor.com/blog/2012/10/17/meteor-050-authentication-user-accounts-new-screencast">blog post</a> is dropped. It took me a second to find the link to the <a href="http://meteor.com/authcast">screencast</a>. When I did, it was like an early Halloween treat. So much sweet, sweet sugar. After talking with everyone, we thought it would be great to try and get someone from the Meteor team to do a TagSoup.</p>

<p>After a few emails, Avital Oliver, JS Engineer at Meteor, agreed. 2 Legit (hay hay)!</p>

<p>With all that said, here's the deets:<br />
When: Nov 15th, 2012 7pm-9pm<br />
Where: <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=Meltmedia&amp;hl=en&amp;cid=13457409171062551353&amp;gl=US&amp;t=m&amp;z=16&amp;iwloc=A">Melt Media</a><br /></p>

<p>Same format as the last meeting with the TypeScript team. Totally open. Ask anything, be prepared, and most important... Have Fun!</p>

<div class="clearfix">
<img class="left" src="/images/legit.png" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/legit.png" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/legit.png" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/legit.png" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/legit.png" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/legit.png" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/legit.png" width="60">
</div>


<!-- /OMG WHAT IS THIS -->



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting Announcement]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/10/09/meeting-announcement/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-09T16:32:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/10/09/meeting-announcement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Picking the brains of Chakra team members Rob and Luke</h3>

<h4>Meeting time and date: 7pm (Arizona Time), Oct 18th, 2012</h4>

<p><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/somasegar/archive/2012/10/01/typescript-javascript-development-at-application-scale.aspx">Recently Microsoft announced a programming language</a> "that solves a very specific problem – getting JavaScript development to scale."</p>

<p>Meet <a href="http://www.typescriptlang.org/">TypeScript</a></p>

<p>There was a lot of chatter on the social outlets. Some positive vibes, some haters and some indifferent. Let's face it though, TS is new and we all have questions. So TagSoup is lucky enough to have a couple TypeScript team members come and chat with us (it's going to be google hangout this time) about their baby. Rob Paveza (Program Manager on the Chakra Team) and Luke Hoban (Principal Program Manager on Chakra and TC39 Committee) from Microsoft are going to be spending some time with us. This isn't going to be a "Presentation" but more of a "Round Table" talk with Rob and Luke. So bring your questions, thoughts and suggestions.</p>

<p>TypeScript caused a huge wave in the JS ocean, but, you don't have to limit your questions for Rob and Luke to just "TypeScript". These guys are great developers and have some powerful thoughts and insight on topics like JavaScipt in general, GRIDS, MV*, Yeoman etc. The idea of these round table discussions is to "knowledge share", learn from each other and make you think in ways that make your brain hurt.</p>

<p>Our friends over at <a href="http://www.meltmedia.com/">Melt Media</a> have stepped up to the plate and offered their building for our meeting location. We will holding the event on Oct 18th, 7pm at Melt Media. We will also be trying our luck with a google hangout broadcast. Fun stuff. We're counting on everyone to create a great discussion and ask as many questions as you'd like.</p>

<div class="clearfix">
<img class="left" src="/images/willyougotomortalkombatpromwithme.gif" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/willyougotomortalkombatpromwithme.gif" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/willyougotomortalkombatpromwithme.gif" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/willyougotomortalkombatpromwithme.gif" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/willyougotomortalkombatpromwithme.gif" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/willyougotomortalkombatpromwithme.gif" width="60">
<img class="left" src="/images/willyougotomortalkombatpromwithme.gif" width="60">
</div>


<!-- / -->



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/07/18/weekly-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-18T16:13:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/07/18/weekly-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh hai!</p>

<p>Come on down to <a href="http://www.cartelcoffeelab.com/cartel-ash-ave-tempe-az/">Cartel Coffee</a> in Tempe, drink some coffee and write some code. We will be there Thursday night (7/19) from 7pm until close.</p>

<p>Some of our friends from <a href="http://www.8byte8.com/">8byte8</a> will be in town and hanging out. Come say hi and show them some AZ love.</p>

<p>See you then!</p>

<p>Tony</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 12th Meet Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/july-12th-meet-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-12T08:52:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/july-12th-meet-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh hai!</p>

<p>Come on down to <a href="http://www.cartelcoffeelab.com/cartel-ash-ave-tempe-az/">Cartel Coffee</a> in Tempe, drink some coffee and write some code. We will be there tonight from 7pm until close.</p>

<p>If you're interested in BackBone.js, we're looking for more people to join the training class put on by Derek Bailey from <a href="http://www.watchmecode.net/">WatchMeCode</a>. Come ask me for the deets.</p>

<p>See you tonight!</p>

<p>Tony</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Meeting Details]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/06/20/weekly-meeting-details/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-20T08:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/06/20/weekly-meeting-details</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey there!</p>

<p>I'm sorry I didn't get to see all your lovely faces last week. I was getting my javascript learn on, in Austin, TX. Tomorrow's meeting (June 21) marks the 4th weekly TagSoup gathering... in a row. OMG . That's a full month. We should TOTALLY celebrate, am I right? So come on down to <a href="http://www.cartelcoffeelab.com/cartel-ash-ave-tempe-az/">Cartel Coffee</a> in Tempe and we can drink some delish coffee and write some code, build X and talk about Y.</p>

<p>Also, some friends are putting together a BackBone.js training class. They have been in contact with Derek Bailey, from watchmecode.net, and have scheduled him to fly out in mid August for a 2 day class. There are a few slots left, and if you're interested, please get a hold of me and I can give you all the details.</p>

<p>See you tomorrow!</p>

<p>Tony</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
