<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Announcement | Phx Tag Soup]]></title>
  <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/categories/announcement/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-09T17:04:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Phx Tag Soup]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting Announcement]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/10/09/meeting-announcement/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-09T16:32:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/10/09/meeting-announcement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>TypeScript from the inside out with Chakra team members Rob and Luke</h3>

<h4>Meeting time and date: 7pm (Arizona Time), Oct 18th, 2012</h4>

<p><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/somasegar/archive/2012/10/01/typescript-javascript-development-at-application-scale.aspx">Recently Microsoft announced their programming language</a> that solves a very specific problem – getting JavaScript development to scale.</p>

<p>Meet <a href="http://www.typescriptlang.org/">TypeScript</a></p>

<p>There was a lot of chatter on the social outlets. Some positive vibes, some haters and some indifferent. Let's face it though, TS is new and we all have questions. So TagSoup is lucky enough to have a couple TypeScript team members come and chat with us (it's going to be google hangout this time) about their baby. Rob Paveza (Program Manager on the Chakra Team) and Luke Hoban (Principal Program Manager on Chakra) from Microsoft are going to be spending some time with us. This isn't going to be a "Presentation" but more of a "Round Table" talk with Rob and Luke. So bring your questions, thoughts and suggestions.</p>

<p>Our friends over at <a href="http://www.meltmedia.com/">Melt Media</a> have stepped up to the plate and offered their building for our meeting location. We will holding the event on Oct 18th, 7pm at Melt Media. We will also be trying our luck with a google hangout broadcast. Fun stuff. We're counting on everyone to create a great discussion and ask as many questions as you'd like.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/07/18/weekly-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-18T16:13:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/07/18/weekly-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh hai!</p>

<p>Come on down to <a href="http://www.cartelcoffeelab.com/cartel-ash-ave-tempe-az/">Cartel Coffee</a> in Tempe, drink some coffee and write some code. We will be there Thursday night (7/19) from 7pm until close.</p>

<p>Some of our friends from <a href="http://www.8byte8.com/">8byte8</a> will be in town and hanging out. Come say hi and show them some AZ love.</p>

<p>See you then!</p>

<p>Tony</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 12th Meet Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/july-12th-meet-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-12T08:52:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/july-12th-meet-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh hai!</p>

<p>Come on down to <a href="http://www.cartelcoffeelab.com/cartel-ash-ave-tempe-az/">Cartel Coffee</a> in Tempe, drink some coffee and write some code. We will be there tonight from 7pm until close.</p>

<p>If you're interested in BackBone.js, we're looking for more people to join the training class put on by Derek Bailey from <a href="http://www.watchmecode.net/">WatchMeCode</a>. Come ask me for the deets.</p>

<p>See you tonight!</p>

<p>Tony</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Meeting Details]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/06/20/weekly-meeting-details/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-20T08:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/06/20/weekly-meeting-details</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey there!</p>

<p>I'm sorry I didn't get to see all your lovely faces last week. I was getting my javascript learn on, in Austin, TX. Tomorrow's meeting (June 21) marks the 4th weekly TagSoup gathering... in a row. OMG . That's a full month. We should TOTALLY celebrate, am I right? So come on down to <a href="http://www.cartelcoffeelab.com/cartel-ash-ave-tempe-az/">Cartel Coffee</a> in Tempe and we can drink some delish coffee and write some code, build X and talk about Y.</p>

<p>Also, some friends are putting together a BackBone.js training class. They have been in contact with Derek Bailey, from watchmecode.net, and have scheduled him to fly out in mid August for a 2 day class. There are a few slots left, and if you're interested, please get a hold of me and I can give you all the details.</p>

<p>See you tomorrow!</p>

<p>Tony</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PhxTagSoup Goes Weekly]]></title>
    <link href="http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/05/23/phxtagsoup-goes-weekly/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-23T12:43:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://TagSoup.github.com/blog/2012/05/23/phxtagsoup-goes-weekly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a lot of feedback from friends, we decided to start holding a TagSoup meeting each week. So, starting May 31st, we will be meeting at <a href="http://www.cartelcoffeelab.com/cartel-ash-ave-tempe-az/">Cartel Coffee</a> each week. Every Thursday night, from 7pm - close, we will be at Cartel. If you want to continue to hang out after hours, Casey Moore's is next door. Take advantage.</p>

<p>May 31st's meeting will be a great time to meet with your teams (from April's meeting) and hopefully wrap up your projects. I know I still have a lot of work to do.</p>

<p>There will be some more announcements made later this week. Hope you all enjoy this news.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
